[
    {
        "question": "What are the only three countries completely surrounded by one other country?",
        "answer": "Lesotho, Vatican City and San Moreno"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country was Indonesia a former colony of?",
        "answer": "The Netherlands"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the only country to have its own official scent?",
        "answer": "Lithuania"
    },
    {
        "question": "The national currency of Panama is named for what Pacific explorer?",
        "answer": "Balboa"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ancient city of Troy was located in what is now what country?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "question": "The White Sea borders what large country?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state is the Grand Coulee Dam?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Germany?",
        "answer": "Berlin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two US states are connected by the Natchez\u2013Vidalia Bridge?",
        "answer": "Mississippi and Louisiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What American discount retail chain is headquartered in Bentonville, Arkansas?",
        "answer": "Walmart"
    },
    {
        "question": "The William J. Clinton Presidential Library is located in which US capital?",
        "answer": "Little Rock, Arkansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the family name of the ruling dynasty of Monaco?",
        "answer": "Grimaldi"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country is the Troi-Rivieres bridge?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kersti Kaljulaid was 46 years old when she became the youngest president ever elected to lead which country?",
        "answer": "Estonia"
    },
    {
        "question": "In geography, what is a skerry?",
        "answer": "A small rocky island."
    },
    {
        "question": "What Australian state shares a nickname with the US state of Florida?",
        "answer": "Queensland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state shares a nickname with the Australian state of Queensland?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "The port of Piraeus serves which European capital?",
        "answer": "Athens"
    },
    {
        "question": "The port of Piraeus is located in which European country?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "The port of Piraeus is located in which country?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Saint Petersburg called for a short period of time before being renamed to Leningrad?",
        "answer": "Petrograd"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the continent of Antarctica, which four countries have no native snakes?",
        "answer": "Ireland, Iceland, Greenland and New Zealand"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mozambique was previously ruled by what European country?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country`s flag is an AK-47 rifle on it?",
        "answer": "Mozambique"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mat\u00e9 is the national drink of which South American Country?",
        "answer": "Argentina -- Mate or mat\u00e9 also known as chimarr\u00e3o or cimarr\u00f3n, is a traditional South American caffeine-rich, infused drink."
    },
    {
        "question": "The dish, Poutine, is a favorite of what country?",
        "answer": "Canada -- Poutine is a dish of french fries and cheese curds topped with a brown gravy."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city is Elfreth`s Alley, the oldest continuously inhabited street in the United States, located?",
        "answer": "Philadelphia -- The street dates back to 1702. It contains 33 houses."
    },
    {
        "question": "Chocolate-chip cookies were invented in which U.S. state?",
        "answer": "Massachusetts -- By Ruth Wakefield in 1938"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United States beach is known as `The Edge of America`?",
        "answer": "Folly Beach, South Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stotinka was a unit of currency in which country?",
        "answer": "Bulgaria"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the main unit of currency in Bulgaria before the introduction of the Euro?",
        "answer": "Lev"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which U.S. state can you find the `City of rocks`?",
        "answer": "Idaho"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European nation is landlocked by a distance of just 6.2 miles?",
        "answer": "San Marino"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Georgia known as in Georgian?",
        "answer": "Sakartvelo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s largest jazz festival?",
        "answer": "Montreal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you see the so-called `Horizontal Waterfalls`?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tirana is the capital of which Eastern European country?",
        "answer": "Albania"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country borders Albania to the south?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "Albania has coasts on which two seas?",
        "answer": "Adriatic and Ionian"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state`s motto is `Live free or die`?",
        "answer": "New Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the highest mountain in the contiguous US?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Mohave lies several miles south of what larger lake?",
        "answer": "Lake Mead"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is nicknamed the `Mount Rushmore State`?",
        "answer": "South Dakota"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the Klamath Mountains?",
        "answer": "Oregon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Monterey Bay is located in what body of water?",
        "answer": "Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "The San Andreas Fault is located in which state?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which three US states have shorelines along Lake Superior?",
        "answer": "Michigan, Minnesota, Wisconsin"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which sea would you find the island of Bornholm?",
        "answer": "Baltic Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Island of Bornhold is part of which country?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Island of Bornhold is part of which European country?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    }
]